女子監獄 第二季 第七集
這里面不用放濾嘴嗎
Yo, shouldn't we be putting filters in these?
濾嘴  我們在哪兒  鄉村俱樂部嗎
Filters? Where we at, the country club?
我們怎么不派發
Ooh, why don't we give 'em out
煙斗和皮草  就像庫伊拉那樣
with cigarette holders and fur coats like Cruella?
電影《101只斑點狗》中的壞女人
還有霍莉·戈萊特麗  她戴小皇冠
And Holly Golightly. She had a tiara.
電影《蒂凡尼的早餐》中的曼哈頓交際花
如果要放濾嘴  就得把香煙卷大些
Put filters in, you got to roll the cigarettes bigger to match.
那樣會減少利潤
Eats into our margins.
你說每支煙換一本食品券
You talkin' 'bout chargin' a book of stamps per,
你到手的利潤已經挺豐厚了
you got pretty good margins already.
-一支煙幾乎九美元  -胡說八道
- That's like nine bucks a smoke. - Oh, shit.
看來沃森
Looks like Watson
知道什么叫供求關系了
is gettin' introduced to our good friends supply and demand.
停手  警衛來了
Cheese it. Fuzz.
水槽里有塊生肉  你能清理下嗎
Would you clean a sink with a piece of raw meat?
你怕有細菌就不肯清理
No, you wouldn't, because of germs.
骯臟的海綿就像塊臭肉
A filthy sponge is like a rectangle of smelly meat.
研究表明
Studies show
浴室水槽里的細菌比廁所還多
that bathroom sinks have more germs in it than a toilet.
-你得消毒  -消毒
- You gotta disinfect! - Disinfect.
你知道哪里的細菌比廁所還多嗎
You know what else has more germs than a toilet?
你的嘴巴
Your mouth.
還有自動取款機的鍵盤和女人的包底
And also ATM keypads and the bottom of ladies' handbags.
我讀到的
I read that.
我們在監獄里每天都能學到新東西呀
You know, we learn something new every day here in prison.
好吧  聽好了  姑娘們
All right. Listen up, ladies.
如果讓顧客選普通郵票和永久郵票
Now, if a customer's got regular stamps and forever stamps,
無論郵費怎么漲  該郵票永遠可以用
她都會選永久郵票
she always take the forever stamps.
所以你就要囤貨
You hold on to those,
等郵局漲價的時候
and when the post office jacks up the prices,
你就賺到了
you've made money.
你是說是你賺的錢  你可是要拿九成
You mean you made money. You taking like 90%, ain't you?
一把郵票弄出去  你的手下就能拿去變錢了
Sendin' those stamps outside, your boys turn 'em into bank.
我可是承擔風險的那個人
I'm the one assuming the risk.
那我還冒著被關禁閉
Uh, what about my risk of sitting in seg
關到瘋掉的危險呢
till I start talkin' to my hand?
你想要零風險  那就走
You want 0%, walk away.
姑娘們  這不僅僅是一樁生意
This is about more than just a business, ladies.
這是為你們自己爭取權益
This is about making something of yourselves.
你給了她們想要的
You give those women something they want,
她們就會因此尊重你
they will respect you for it.
我干完了
Yeah. I'm done.
很好  交給美味
That's very good. Give 'em to Taystee.
可它們都是我做的
But they're mine.
我們談過  蘇珊娜  還記得嗎
We had this talk, Suzanne. Remember?
我們每個人都有技能
We each have skills.
但你沒有推銷的技能
Salesmanship, not one of yours.
得讓別人樂意才會買
Gotta make people feel more comfortable.
維  我們要把這些貨放哪里
Yo, Vee, where we supposed to keep all of these?
我可不想關禁閉
'Cause a sister is not tryin' to go to SHU.
你有什么隱身斗篷之類的嗎
You got some kind of invisibility cloak or somethin'?
你說對了
You could say that.
是我要求太高了嗎
Am I asking too much here?
我有強加給你們什么辦不到的事嗎
Am I putting something on you people that you physically can't do,
像是跳探戈之類的
like dance the tango or something?
沒有  我是要你們稱職點
No. I'm asking for competence.
首先  讓囚犯待在監獄里
For starters, keeping the prisoners in prison.
在我看來相當簡單
Seems pretty simple to me.
別穿著沾了水果蛋糕的卡其褲
Not having a fruitcake in khakis
在大家面前走來走去
wander around in public,
要五個警衛押她出去
five officers hustling her out,
塞進車里  該死的就像小丑表演
putting her in a car like some kind of fucking clown show.
我在說你呢  本尼特
I'm talkin' to you, Bennett.
-是你把我一人丟在這兒的  -胡說
- You left me here alone. - That is false.
我當時也在這里
Yeah, I was here.
對  你拿著《鱸魚大師》雜志到處晃
Yeah, you were patrolling a copy of Bassmaster Magazine.
我只是要很恭敬地說一句
I'm just saying, respectfully,
也許情人節并不是
that maybe Valentine's wasn't the best day
帶著一堆人去酒吧看你表演的最佳時機
to take a bunch of people to see your gig at a bar.
又不是之前沒人出去過
It's not like people haven't gotten out before.
送她去重刑監獄  刑期再多加幾年
Take her to Max, stick a few years on her sentence.
這女人都坐了一輩子牢了
The woman's 100 years old.
還要給她加刑
We're gonna give her more time?
貝爾  我要你對那個囚犯實施全方位盯人
Bell, I want you all over that inmate like a fly on shit.
你跟著她  找出她逃走的路線
You follow her. You find out how she's running.
我們就好好問問她怎么樣
How about we just ask her?
我已經問過了
I already did.
她告訴我她是從27街拿到手推車的
She told me she took the trolley from 27th Street.
等我們把這個漏洞堵上
I will deal with this officially
我會正式處理這件事
when we get the hole plugged up.
你要我整天盯著菲利斯·狄勒
You want me 'round the clock babysittin' Phyllis Diller?
如果你覺得浪費了你的才能和學識就告訴我
Let me know if that is a waste of your talents and education.
第二  記過配額指標
Second, shot quota.
我們得把這里好好整頓一番
We are gonna straighten things up around here.
我要你們每人每周至少記過五筆
I want each of you writing five shots a week minimum.
讓這些姑娘們老實點
Keep these ladies on point.
-你要記過六筆  -這不公平
- And for you, it's six. - That's not fair.
我要你對她們狠點  我會盯著你完成的
I asked you to toughen up your game. I'll see you gettin' there.
這要煩死人了  卡普托
Gonna be such a bitch, Caputo.
光是文書工作就很煩
The paperwork alone.
去跟你媽說  也許她會給你寫個便條
Tell it to your mom. Maybe she'll write you a fuckin' note.
滾出去
Get out.
犯人  你點名遲到了
Inmate. You're late for count.
-還有45秒  -你來不及走到那里
- I got 45 seconds still. - Not enough time to get there.
這算什么  《少數派報告》
What is this, The Minority Report?
抱歉  我要給你記上一筆
Sorry. I'm gonna write you a shot.
什么你  白人妞辛迪也遲到了啊
What you... White Cindy ain't gonna make it, either.
我看的不是白人妞辛迪
I ain't looking at White Cindy.
這絕對是種族歧視了吧
This is some racism right here!
不是  不過如果你不閉嘴就會算了
It's not. But it's about to be if you don't shut up.
這他媽的算什么意思
What the hell that even mean?
趴在地上  犯人
Get down on the ground, inmate.
你他媽在跟我開玩笑
Fucking kidding me?
我剛才說什么了
What'd I just say?
好吧  動作快點  公民們
All right, let's move it, people.
把你的鞋子脫了
And take your shoes off.
我都不知道我為什么還要廢話
I don't even know why I even got to say it.
抱歉  我請你把汽水扔掉
Oh! Excuse me. I'm gonna need you to throw out that soda.
我還在喝呢
I'm still drinking it.
你還在喝
You still drinkin' it?
恐怖分子也是這么說的
That's what the terrorists say.
你是恐怖分子嗎
You a terrorist?
扔掉
Throw it out!
拜托  快點  走  你  快點
Come on, people. Let's move it. Let's go. You, come on.
-好了  -小心點  女士
- Oh, yeah! - Watch it, lady.
讓路
Move out the way!
機場緊急救援
Airport emergency.
到手
Got it!
棒呆
Oh, yeah!
中頭獎了  寶貝
Ooh. Jackpot, baby. Ah. Mmm.
姑娘  我差不多都有11個了
Oh, girl. I got, like, 11 of those.
那個應該是防水的
That one's supposed to be waterproof.
我跟你說  姑娘
Let me tell you, girl,
你往它上面撒點狂暴果汁  會大事不妙
you get some Crunk Juice on that shit, not good.
紅牛加軒尼詩混合飲料
看起來我們有麻煩了
Looks like we got a problem here.
我沒問題的
I'm clean.
嚴格來說  是的
Technically, yes.
可是我不能讓你肌肉緊繃上飛機
But I can't let you on the plane with these guns.
轉身
Turn around.
能接到你的消息我很驚訝
I was surprised to get your note.
老實說  萊瑞并不太合作
To be honest, Larry wasn't all that cooperative.
萊瑞最近心情不太好
Well, Larry's in a weird place these days,
可以說是我的錯
which is mostly my fault.
但我不能細說
But I can't get into that.
跟我無關  我只是很高興他們讓我進來
It's none of my business. I'm just glad they let me in.
有時候  低效率也挺好的
Sometimes, inefficiency works for you.
事情是這樣的
Here's the thing.
我奶奶病得很重  我應該獲得休假的
My grandmother is very sick, and I'm supposed to get furlough,
可是看起來好像沒戲
but it doesn't seem to be happening.
我不知道跟我有什么關系
I'm not sure where I come in.
就是監獄制度不合理的典型案例
Just one example of how the prison system isn't working.
警衛瀆職  濫用單獨禁閉
Guard misconduct, overuse of solitary confinement.
外面的人應該知道里面是怎么回事
People on the outside should know what it's like.
帕波  監獄對待犯人本來就不公平
Piper, prison treats inmates unfairly.
如果周末不能放假回家探親
If not getting a weekend off to visit the family
是最糟糕的事
is the worst thing...
我根本沒說
I didn't even remotely say...
犯人挨餓  被強暴
Inmates are starving. They're getting raped.
并非沒人報道
And it's not like no one's covering this.
只是沒人在乎罷了
It's just that no one cares.
聽著  我有過夜不能寐
Listen, do I lie awake
幻想憑一己之力
fantasizing about personally taking down an institution
靠幾句鏗鏘有力的話
that is the single greatest stain
就推翻自奴隸制之后
on the American collective conscience
美國集體良知的最大污點嗎
since slavery with the awesome power of my words?
當然
Sure.
可是在白天  我接受現實  這不可能的
But in the daytime, I've accepted that's not gonna happen.
我能做的  也許就是
What I can do, maybe,
查明利奇菲爾德消失的兩百萬去了哪里
is find $2 million that's gone off the books here at Litchfield.
你想要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
如果錢被挪用了  肯定是用到了某處
If money's being appropriated, it has to be going somewhere.
我猜錢都支付到一個
I'm guessing that there's some kind of shell corporation
空殼公司去了
it's being paid into.
電網的確有點問題
There is something going on with the electrical grid.
這里都歸菲格羅亞管
Well, Figueroa's the official on the ground here,
也就是說要么她被愚弄了
which means that she's either being duped
要么她就是黑手
or she's in on the profits.
我要知道誰跟她訂了協議
And I need to know who she's making contracts with
誰干活  誰供貨
for labor, supplies,
她給誰開支票
who she's writing checks to.
好吧  好的  我會去他們為了
Okay, cool. I'll just look that up
方便我們調查我們感興趣的事
in the handy inmate Internet they give us for
而提供的囚犯網絡上查查的
when we get curious about stuff.
他們去年花了20萬美元
They appropriated $200,000 last year
翻修了一個并不存在的健身房
to renovate a gym that doesn't exist.
我很想幫你  我會幫你的
Look, I would love to help you. I really would.
但是除了闖進菲格的辦公室
But short of breaking into Fig's office
檢查她的文件
and going through her files,
我不知道我該干什么
I'm not sure what I'm supposed to do.
我已經被關過兩次禁閉了
I have been thrown in SHU twice already,
我很愛我奶奶  她可能就要死了
and I love my grandmother, and she could die.
我不會為了當個小間諜
I'm not gonna fuck things up for myself
美國喜劇電影
冒大風險給自己惹麻煩
by playing high-stakes Harriet the Spy.
好吧  如果你改變主意了就告訴我
Okay. Let me know if you change your mind.
對你奶奶的情況表示遺憾
I'm sorry about your grandmother.
你確定你就要做通常的發型
You sure you just want the usual?
所以才叫"通常"嘛
That's why it's called "the usual".
現在廚房都歸你管
I mean, you're running the kitchen now.
你可以展示一下氣場
You got room for a statement.
什么  我該把頭發染成紫紅色嗎
What, should I dye my hair fuchsia?
是赤褐色  可惜不適合你
It's auburn. But not for you.
我覺得一個勁爆的莫西干頭
I think a nice faux-hawk will give that
就能告訴別人"別惹我"
"Don't fuck with me" vibe, you know?
我主要靠臉來震懾別人
I mostly use my face for that.
喂  發膠
Hey, Aqua Net,
紅媽讓跟你說她開始種紫羅蘭了
Red said to tell you she's got violets growing.
我難道應該在意這件事嗎  為什么
And I should give a shit about this, why?
她說你會想知道的
She said you'd wanna know.
她想種什么就種什么  我不
She can grow whatever she wants. I don't give a...
紫羅蘭
Violets.
你是對的  我會去看看的
Oh. You're right. I'll come check that out.
這里每天都讓我越來越困惑
Every day in this place, I get more confused.
你帶券了嗎
Did you bring the stamps?
你為什么不先說說
Why don't you first tell me
是什么會讓我超級興奮
what I'm supposed to be so hair-on-fire excited about?
聽著  多謝你的關心
Man, look, I appreciate your concern,
不過我衛生巾夠用
but I'm actually well covered on the menstruation front.
就來一支
Just take one.
萬福瑪麗亞  你充滿圣寵
Hail Mary, full of grace.
他媽的我要怎么點燃這個
Yeah, how the hell am I supposed to light this?
要鉆木取火嗎
What, I gotta rub two sticks together or something?
好好看著  利奇菲爾德牌打火機
Behold the Litchfield lighter.
我勒個去
Get the fuck out.
這可以算是我人生中排第三的好日子了
Man, it's like the third-best day of my entire life.
往下水道里噴
Man, blow into the drain!
然后評論家改了主意
What happened was the critic changed his mind
因為燉老鼠很美味
because the rat made stew, and it was delicious.
我明白
I understand that,
不過光靠燉老鼠可開不了餐館
but that doesn't mean the rat can open a restaurant.
衛生法典還是要遵守的
The health code is still the health code.
你好像心死了
It's like you're dead inside.
我聽說有什么紫羅蘭
Um, I heard something about violets?
關門
Close the door.
你們居然會輸掉冷戰真是不可思議
It is a mystery to me how you people ever lost the Cold War.
等等
But wait.
用這個給我染發
This covers this.
你有被一個六英尺高的變性黑女人吻過嗎
You ever been kissed by a 6-foot, black, transgender woman?
不用了  謝謝  不過我的小賣部需要幫忙
I'm good, thanks. But my commissary could use some love.
不是以貨換服務嗎
Whatever happened to goods for services?
我手頭的現金有點吃緊
I'm running a little dry in the cash department.
你的貨流渠道很穩定吧
You got a steady channel, I assume?
你想要什么就有什么
Whatever you want.
如果要求合理
Within reason.
我會回來的
I'll be back.
你在開玩笑吧
You cannot be serious.
弗洛雷斯
Flores!
那堆拉美人連像樣的米飯和豆子都做不好
Bunch of Latinas can't make decent rice and beans.
到底是哪里出了問題
What's wrong with this picture?
我是吃中餐長大的
I grew up eating Chinese.
那時候我繼父叫陳東  他有好多頭皮屑
My stepdad from then was named Chen Dong. He had so much dandruff.
就是那個黑胡椒
It's that black pepper.
盒裝的爛貨  嘗起來就像我外婆的骨灰
The shit that comes in boxes, it tastes like my abuela's ashes.
有次我叔叔烤了只被他碾死的穿山甲
One time my uncle cooked an armadillo he hit with his car.
味道還不錯
It tastes okay
不過得放點辣椒醬才行
but you gotta put Cholula on it.
-現在有點忙  -抱歉  我該不該
- Kind of busy right now. - Sorry. Should I...
圣誕老人
Santa?
圣誕老人個鬼
Fuck Santa.
本尼特比圣誕老人帥氣
Bennett's better looking
哪怕你不守規矩他也會給你禮物
and he shows up even if you've been naughty.
你那是什么
What'd you get?
這些玩意越來越小巧玲瓏了
Oh, these things just keep getting smaller.
其實都是我的
That's actually mine.
你可以借幾天  但我要拿回來的
You can borrow it for a few days, but I'm gonna need it back.
都是艦隊狐貍的歌
Ugh. It's full of Fleet Foxes and shit.
-我的手機呢  -白人妞  現實點
- What about my phone? - Blanca, be real.
聽著  這是我最后一次這么做了
Look, this is the last time that I can do this.
好吧  我不要手機  我要色情雜志
Okay, fuck the phone but I want porn.
老兄  弗洛雷斯真他媽是個天才
Oh, man. Flores is a fucking genius!
好吧  不過要高檔點的
Okay, but good porn.
不要日本人那種變態的瞎扯淡
None of that weird Japanese bullshit.
我要只有男人的雜志
And I want a magazine with just guys in it.
怎么了  很性感啊
What? It's hot.
還有  我又不想看女人
And plus, I don't wanna be exploiting women and shit.
一點性欲都沒有
It sucks out all the sexy.
我不會買同性戀色情雜志的
I'm not buying gay porn.
你是恐同人士嗎
Are you homophobic or something?
各位  夠了
Suficiente, everyone!
外面都是餓肚子的人  快點
We got hungry people out there. Vamos!
我大概會餓死
I may starve to death.
不用說  我是素食主義者
I'm a vegetarian, obviously.
我表示尊重  但是  此時此地
You know, and I respect that, but under the present circumstances,
我相當肯定  即使是
I'm pretty sure that even...
保羅·麥卡特尼也會對金槍魚砂鍋投降的
even Paul McCartney would be all up in a tuna casserole.
甲殼蟲樂隊樂手  素食主義者
看那個沙拉  就是冰凍豌豆和卷心萵苣
Look. That salad bar, it's just frozen peas and iceberg lettuce.
我要堅果  我要蔬菜
I need nuts. I need legumes.
-查普曼  -怎么
- Hey, Chapman? - Mmm-hmm?
你覺得我和岡薩雷斯
You think that me and Gonzales
能幫你一起弄監獄簡報嗎
could help you out with that newsletter thing?
-是的  再好不過了  -好吧
- Yeah, sure. That would be great. - Okay.
雖然可能有點奇怪
This might be weird,
但是你知道廚房的供貨商嗎
but do you know anything about the kitchen vendors?
比如雜貨是哪個公司送的
Like which company delivers the groceries?
開卡車的人嗎
Some guys in a truck.
-蘇蘇  -不要
- Soso? - No.
豬比狗要聰明
Pigs are smarter than dogs.
你吃蛋嗎
Do you eat eggs?
那要看它是怎么被飼養的
Depends on how they were raised.
不吃唄
So, no.
你想拿我開玩笑就開
Okay, make fun of me if you want,
但是這個國家的農產品行業
but the agro-business complex in this country
真是完全瘋了
is completely insane.
賤人  看看你周圍
Bitch, look around you.
我們在監獄里
We in the prison-business complex.
如果奶牛能讓我離開這里
A cow breaks me out of here,
那我就不再吃肉
I'll stop eating meat that day.
是真的嗎
Is it true?
非洲的天主教牧師允許結婚
That the Catholic priests in Africa are allowed to get married
就因為對他們而言守貞太難
because chastity's just too hard for them?
我覺得對每個人而言都很難
I think it's hard for anyone.
對  但要是非洲男人
Yeah, but African men?
那又是另當別論了
That's a whole other story.
我相信你的話  失陪了
I'll take your word for it. Excuse me.
-姊妹  玉米面包  -哦
- Sister, the cornbread. - Oh.
就是我有低血糖  你記得嗎
It's that darn blood-sugar thing. You remember.
我得給你記上一筆
I'm gonna have to write you a shot.
你要給修女記過
You'd give a shot to a nun?
不要恨我
Don't hate me.
我還從來沒有被記過過
I've never gotten a shot before.
好日子到頭了  真的
It's the end of days. I'm telling you.
行了
Okay.
-需要幫忙嗎  -哦
- Can I help with this? - Oh.
謝謝  羅伯塔
Thank you, Roberta.
不客氣
You're welcome.
昨晚我看見我丈夫了
I saw my husband last night.
聽起來真不錯
Well, that sounds lovely.
他現在玩貝斯了
He plays the bass now.
別忘了擦這些鞋子
Don't forget to shine those shoes.
我說過會給你理床  但不包括這些鞋子
Now, I said I'd clean your bunk. The shoes are not included.
我雖不是科學家什么的
I ain't saying I'm no scientist or nothing,
但鞋子也在這個床鋪里  對嗎
but the shoes in the bunk, correct?
光是待在這兒我可能就會被記過
Look, I'm gonna get a shot for even being in here.
如果我要再次面對紀律仲裁委員會
If I have to go in front of the disciplinary board one more time...
因果報應  你們白人是自食其果
You know, karma-wise, your people had this coming.
行了  這就是我能拿到的
Okay, yo. Here's what I got.
等等  我明確說過要草莓的
Oh, hold up. I specifically said strawberry.
我們沒草莓的了
Well, we're out of strawberry right now.
那是我能拿到最好的了
That's the best I could do, all right?
我知道的是
All I know is...
我手里有高級貨
I'm holding some premium shit here.
賤人  我不抽煙好嗎
Bitch, I don't even smoke, okay?
我要用它收買阿蕾達  讓她借我熱水管
I need it to bribe Aleida to let me borrow her stinger
我好用熱蠟除掉我的胡子
so I can wax my mustache.
幸虧你遇到我心情不錯
Guess you caught me in a soft mood.
生日快樂  親愛的
Happy birthday, baby.
-跟你姐姐說謝謝  -謝謝
- Say "thank you" to your sister. - Thank you!
有一陣子沒見你了
It's been a while since we saw you.
你知道  工作真的很忙
You know, things been real busy at work,
不過我不會錯過小個子的生日  絕不會
but I wouldn't go missing Shorty's birthday, no way!
我靠
Oh, shit!
-莫妮卡  -對不起
- Monica! - Sorry.
過來
Bring it here.
然后
Then... Unh.
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
對一個九歲孩子而言有點過了
A little much for a 9-year-old.
你要是想說有點招搖  那你就說對了
Yeah, if you mean a little much swagger, you got that right!
我希望你能陪我過每個生日
I wish you were here for all my birthdays.
去年媽媽給我買了衣服
Last year, Mom got me clothes.
那是你需要的  寶貝
It's what you needed, baby.
我們去吃冰激凌怎么樣  就我們倆
Hey, how about we go for some ice cream, you and me?
-好的  -過幾小時就吃晚飯了
- Yes! - Dinner is in a few hours.
今天是個特殊的日子
It's a special occasion.
-你想要什么口味  -泡泡糖的
- What flavor you want? - Bubble gum!
我們仨一起去怎么樣
How 'bout we all go together?
你擔心什么
What you so nervous about?
你以為呢  我昨天才認識你嗎
What you think, I met you yesterday?
我會看著她的  我保證
Look, I'm gonna look out for her. I promise.
她保證  媽媽
She promised, Mom.
去吧  但是要把iPad留這里
Go ahead. But leave that iPad here.
我不想你把它弄丟了或者被偷了
I don't want you losin' it or gettin' it stolen.
我們快走吧
Let's blow this joint!
-辛迪  -我知道
- Cindy. - I know.
查普曼  我就是想
Hey, Chapman, I was just wondering
你的簡報委員會還缺不缺人
if maybe you got any room on your newsletter committee,
也許我也可以加入嗎
that maybe I could join up?
我想想  目前就我和兩個西班牙姑娘
Let me see. So far, it's me and two Spanish girls,
其中一個有點把我嚇到了  所以  行
one of whom scares me a little bit, so, yeah.
我想我可以把你排進來
Yeah, I think I can squeeze you in.
真的太棒了
Oh, that's really good.
你有什么特別想寫的嗎
Is there anything in particular that you wanna write about?
我還沒想那么遠
Uh, I didn't really get that far.
我只是覺得讓自己忙起來會比較好
I just thought it'd be good to keep busy, you know?
寫寫愛情小說怎么樣
Well, what about romance?
像是長篇連載什么的
Like a serial type of thing?
狄更斯跟丹尼爾·斯蒂爾混合體
Dickens meets Danielle Steel.
我不想去碰愛情類的東西
I'm trying to stay away from the romance-type stuff,
-就是這一陣子  -哦
- just for a little while. - Oh.
沒事  只是  也許可以寫寫其他的
Oh, yeah. No, it's fine. It's just, maybe something else.
很操蛋  對吧
It's fucked up, isn't it?
我們被困在這里
How we're stuck in here
可是外面的世界不斷在變化
and the world outside just keeps turning?
是啊
Yeah.
寫個美容專欄怎么樣
What about a beauty column?
你總是那么漂亮
You always look so nice.
你知道  雖然你在監獄里
Well, you know, just 'cause you're in prison
但并不意味著你就能不管不顧了
don't mean you got to let it go.
我敢肯定你有些很好的美容心得
I bet that you have some great tips.
好吧  好吧  我可以寫  我可以寫
Okay. Okay. I can do it. I can do that.
謝謝你  查普曼
Thank you, Chapman.
-你有煙嗎  -什么
- Hey, you got a fag? - A what?
煙  吸煙  煙頭  抽煙
A fag. You know, a drag. A butt. A burn.
你是說香煙  你跑錯地方了
Look, you talking about cigarettes, you're at the wrong house.
拜托
Come on, I'm not the one
又不是我開了黑人煙館
who started a Negro-League Tobacco Shack, all right?
那是你的好朋友  維
That would be your pal Vee.
我只是想弄點好貨
I merely seek to avail myself of a fine product.
她不是我朋友
She ain't my pal.
她朋友跟你朋友在一起
She's pals with your pals.
對  她就是利用你們給她賣命
Right, or she's using them to do her dirt
她只要數錢就行了
while she counts the cash.
她不會被發現跟違禁品有任何關系
You ain't gonna find her hands on no contraband.
你看著吧  如果有人因為運貨被抓
You watch, somebody goes down for carrying,
她會在獄警面前裝傻陪笑
she'll be shuffling and smiling in front of the COs like,
"上帝  這些姑娘干什么壞事了"
"Oh, Lord, what have these girls got up to?"
媽的
Fuck.
你知道高中生女同性戀的遭遇嗎
Hey, you know that thing that happens to lesbians in high school?
我們和喜歡的直女
How we strike up a really intense best-friendship
建立起親密的閨蜜關系的
with a straight girl who's really into it.
我們會勸自己能做朋友就很好  對嗎
And we convince ourselves that friends is good, right?
直到她有了男朋友
Until she gets a boyfriend.
我們討厭那個缺德鬼
We hate that poor asshole
討厭到天怒人怨
with the white-hot heat of a thousand suns,
還說些"他配不上你"之類的話
a "He's not worthy of you," or whatever,
盡管他可能是個相當不錯的人
when he's probably a decent-enough person, i mean, as guys go.
因為我們
Because what's really happening
其實是愛上了我們的朋友
is that we're in love with our friend.
為什么大家都覺得我愛上了她  我沒有
Yo, why does everybody think I'm in love with her? 'Cause I'm not.
當然  當然  你要這么想就這么想吧
Sure. Sure. Let's go with that.
不過如果你的確是喜歡她
But in the event that you were having the feels for her?
你討厭她的男朋友
Yeah, it turns out that by hating her boyfriend,
其實只會把她從你身邊推開
you're just gonna drive her away.
你得接受這件事并讓他喜歡你
I mean, you gotta suck it up and make him like you.
打打牌  把《教父》看十遍什么的
Take up poker. Watch The Godfather 10 times or whatever.
各位  警報解除  我們找到了
All clear, everybody. We found it.
不管怎樣  這是你的人生
Anyway, it's your life.
你想怎么揮霍都行
I mean, spend it how you want, all right?
你的袋子呢  圣誕老人
Ay, where's your sack, Santa?
我做不到
Couldn't do it.
好吧  我再也不會這么做了
Okay, I'm not doing this anymore.
我看你是忘了敲詐是怎么回事了  老大
I think you forgot how blackmail works, papi.
我看你是忘了監獄是怎么回事了
I think you forgot how prison works.
這太過分了  好嗎
This shit has gone too far, okay?
你知道還有誰很過分嗎  你跟達婭娜
You know who else went too far? You with Dayanara.
好吧  這個怎么樣
Fine. How about this?
你們都被記過了
You're all getting shots.
我什么都沒干  混蛋
Yo, I didn't do nothing, asshole.
好吧  那你真可憐
Well, that sucks for you.
你他媽是在跟我開玩笑吧
You gotta be fucking kidding me, right?
我發誓我沒在開玩笑
I promise you I'm not kidding.
本尼特
Hey, Bennett,
如果卡普托發現你強奸了囚犯會怎么樣
what's gonna happen when Caputo finds out you raped an inmate?
-他不會發現的  -你確定
- He's not gonna find out. - You sure about that?
對  我很確定
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
因為你馬上要被關禁閉了  拉莫斯
'Cause you're going to the SHU, Ramos.
-為什么  -我要再想想
- For what? - I'll figure it out later.
-你不會那么對我的  -你覺得我不會
- You ain't gonna do that to me. - You think I'm not?
走  動作快點
Let's go. Move it!
媽的
Shit!
你要跟她一起關禁閉
You wanna join her?
再見
Bye.
沒想到這雜種還有這膽子
I didn't think that fucker had it in him.
我聽說你想見我
I heard you wanted to see me?
查普曼  對的  請進
Uh, Chapman. Right. Come in.
卡普托先生  你有沒有
Mr. Caputo, have you, um,
聽到關于我休假申請的事
heard anything about my furlough request?
那不歸我管  抱歉
It's not my department. Sorry.
不過我在考慮你的簡報的事
But I've been thinking about this newsletter.
很棒
Awesome.
我想這會是一個很好的渠道
I've been thinking it could be a good way
讓我們管理層
for us, the administration,
能夠跟你們囚犯進行溝通
to communicate with the inmates.
來解釋我們的立場
Explain our side of things.
你的立場是什么
Your side of what?
例如  現在實行的記過配額指標
For instance, this shot-quota thing we got going.
你們覺得我們刻薄
You ladies think we're being mean.
但我們只是做了本職工作
But we're just doing our job, you know?
事情變得失控  對大家都沒好處
Things get out of hand, it's bad for everybody.
法西斯主義也是這么說的
That's kind of what fascists say.
我媽媽那邊可能跟墨索里尼沾親
I may be related to Mussolini on my mother's side.
開個玩笑
It's a joke.
也許你可以在簡報里寫點警衛的事
Maybe you could put something in the newsletter about the guards.
說明我們大家都是人
Show everybody we're human.
警衛  和我們一樣
"Guards, they're just like us."
這就有點過了
I wouldn't go that far.
這個怎么樣  "警衛
How about, "Guards...
他們也是人"
they're people, too"?
那么
So, uh...
告訴我
tell me...
你業余時間喜歡干什么
what do you like to do in your spare time?
你好
Hi.
-你是怎么回事啊  -好多事呢
- What is the matter with you? - So much.
你性致高昂地出現在我家
You show up at my house like fucking Squiggy with a hard-on.
你下次決定向丈夫最近才買了阿留申群島狩獵矛
Maybe next time you decide to make some deranged declaration
而且乳導管堵塞的感情白癡
of love to an emotional zombie with a blocked milk duct
發表瘋狂的愛的宣言的時候
and a husband who recently purchased an Aleutian hunting spear,
能先給我打個電話嗎
you could consider calling first?
好吧  聽著  波麗  我有點失控了
Okay, look, Polly, I'm spiraling out, okay? I am.
你知道有時候人設想生活應該是怎么樣的
You know, you have this idea of what your life is supposed to...
不  我辦不到  拉瑞
No, I can't do this, Larry!
好吧
Okay.
我認真的  這太傻逼了
I'm serious. It's just stupid.
我知道
I know.
沒錯
I mean, yes,
我們跟皮特和帕波約會前就是朋友
we were friends before we even started dating Pete and Piper.
我臨產的時候  是你把我送到醫院
And yes, you drove me to the hospital when I was in labor
辦理了所有的書面材料  還細心照看我
and handled all the paperwork and the nurses.
當我丈夫消失不見
And yes, you were the only one there for me
去執行為期一個月的自我探索任務時
when my husband checked out of fatherhood
你是唯一在我身邊幫我的人
so he could go on a month-long mission of self-exploration,
你很風趣  又恰到好處的一本正經
and you're funny, but also boring in all the right ways, and...
我到底在說什么  操我吧
What the hell am I saying? Just fuck me.
-我不知道這意味著什么  -閉嘴
- I don't know what this means. - Shut up.
好吧  聽著  聽著
Okay, listen, listen.
我好幾個月沒有性生活了
I haven't had sex in months,
所以我比較有可能
so there's a better-than-average chance that I could...
閉嘴  拉瑞
Just shut the fuck up, Larry.
你有說過什么乳導管堵塞嗎
Did you say something about a blocked milk duct?
玩右邊那個就好
Just stay to the right.
就像寄信一樣
It's like sending a letter.
有個窗口  你輸入問題答案就出來了
There's a box, you type in a question, and the answer comes up.
是誰在另一端查答案
Who's on the other end looking it up?
沒人  都在電線里
Nobody. It's in the wires.
里面有世界上所有的信息
It's all the information in the world.
你說世界上所有的信息都藏在電線里
You're telling me all the information in the world is in wires?
但是人們還是很愚蠢  對嗎
But people are still stupid, right?
紅媽  我需要些火柴
Hey, Red. I could really use some matches.
火柴
Matches.
-對  -很好
- Yeah. - Good.
我剛還在想我們死在
I was just thinking our chances of dying
瘋子縱火犯的燃燒彈下的幾率還不夠高呢
in some nut-job arsonist's fire bomb weren't high enough already.
我不會讓其他任何人接觸到它們的
I wouldn't let anyone else touch 'em.
拜托  我只是想抽支煙
Come on. I'm just trying to get my smoke on.
你有什么可抽呢
And what exactly are you smoking?
黑人有香煙
The black girls got cigs.
你需要打手
You need muscle,
塔斯利茲曾用斧頭砍死過人
Taslitz killed a guy with an ax.
那時候她還沒得關節炎
That was before the arthritis.
大波  雖然我很想幫你
Boo, much as I'd like to help you
讓你下半輩子都關禁閉  可是我沒空
spend the rest of your life in solitary, I'm busy.
你待會兒過來
Come back later
我會考慮給你點曲奇什么的
and I'll see about getting you some cookies or something.
真是的
Oh, man.
記一過  犯人
That's a shot, inmate.
為什么
For what?
損壞公共財物
Damaging government property.
胡說八道  你心里清楚得很
That is horse shit, and you know it.
你還想記一筆罵臟話嗎
You want one for obscenity, too?
我覺得羅娜可以擔任副主編
So, I'm thinking that Lorna can be assistant editor,
幫我們想想寫點什么話題
help us come up with ideas of things to write about
還有誰來寫
and people to write them.
所以你讓兩個白人妞來負責
So you got two white girls in charge?
該死的
Ah, shit.
我覺得應該讓有能力的人擔任  就這些
I just think it should be based on who earned it, is all.
我高中負責過年鑒  所以
I did yearbook in high school, so...
年鑒根本不是正式刊物
Yearbook isn't even a real class.
就是拍點照片  抽點大麻  大家都懂
You just take photographs and smoke weed. Everybody knows that.
不管怎樣  我已經寫了一個專欄
Anyway, I already wrote a column.
-我看看  -喂
- Let me see. - Hey.
這是我畫的
Look, I drew this.
是關于監獄里的情況
It's about being in jail with,
用動物園里的動物作比
like, animals at the zoo.
為什么海象的心情這么差
Why is the walrus in such a bad mood?
那是海利先生
Oh. That's, um, Mr. Healy.
精彩絕倫
This is fantastic.
-你已經寫錯了  -誰說的
- You already made your first mistake. - Says who?
如果你能"少在乎一點"
If you "could care less,"
在口語里是couldn't care less的訛用
說明你還是在乎的
that means you still care.
懂嗎
You know what I'm saying?
你當然可以少在乎一點
'Cause, like, it is possible for you to care less.
不對不對  我是說無論你有多在乎
No. No. I'm saying is however much you care,
我都不在乎
I could care less than you.
這句話不是這個意思
That's not what it means.
你應該說"我一點也不在乎"  懂嗎
It should be, "I couldn't care less." See?
因為你的結論還是在乎的
Because you hit bottom with caring.
查普曼  跟她說說
Yo, Chapman, tell her.
嚴格來說  是的
I mean, technically, yes.
但我覺得就像"照字面意思"這個詞一樣
But I think this is one of those things like "literally",
口語中常表示真的  確實
最后總是越口語化的用法越被人接受
where the colloquial usage of the word eventually wins out.
語言是不斷發展的
Languages evolve.
你為什么要那樣
Why you gotta be like that?
關鍵是每個人都知道我要說什么
Look, the point is everybody knows what I'm trying to say.
你為什么非要犯渾呢
Why you gotta be a dick about it?
那叫語法  蠢貨
It's called grammar, tonta.
我很高興我總算找到你了  羅伯塔
I'm so glad I found you, Roberta.
-你還好嗎  -不好  我被人跟蹤了
- Are you okay? - No. I'm being followed.
是該死的愛爾蘭人  我不能回大房間去
It's the damn Irish. I can't go back to the pen.
不準肢體接觸  卡瓦諾
No touching, Cavanaugh.
太悲哀了
Oh, that is so sad.
你打算寫什么
What are you gonna write about?
我在考慮  建議專欄
I was thinking, like, an advice column.
大家寫下自己的問題
People write about their problems,
然后我會讓她們振作起來
and then I tell them to get their shit together.
有一堆棒球類的呢  我最喜歡了
Mmm. Got a bunch of the baseball ones. My favorite.
有我在  你可以高枕無憂了
You know I got you covered.
-辛迪  -怎么
- Cindy. - Yo.
有什么要給我的嗎
Got something for me?
事實是  沒有
Oh. So, here's the thing. No.
也許你愿意來解釋一下
Maybe you'd care to explain.
不是每個人都有券
Not everyone had stamps.
她們不知道你會找她們要券
They didn't know you was gonna be looking for 'em.
但不代表就不該給她們煙抽
Doesn't mean they shouldn't get a smoke.
其實  就是那個意思
Well, actually, that's exactly what it means.
這就叫生意
It's called commerce.
我讓她們按老辦法交易
I let 'em trade for it old school,
就像印第安人那樣
like the red man.
賤人  相信我  你該給維的必須給
Bitch, trust me, you do not wanna short Vee.
她會化身金剛狼揍你
She will go Wolverine on your ass.
好吧  聽著
All right, listen.
后面的煙我會多賣幾塊錢
I'll sell the next ones for a couple bucks extra,
好補差價
make up the difference.
如果你整包賣不好  你就別賣了
If you can't be trusted with the package, you can't be selling.
從現在起  你去做維護
From now on, you're on maintenance.
那是什么意思
What that supposed to mean?
就是你去干蘇珊娜干的活
You do what Suzanne's been doing.
你給賣煙的人卷煙
You roll smokes for everyone to sell,
打包  收尾
package them, sweep up behind.
我不要干苦差事
I ain't doing no grunt work.
等你還清了債
When you've paid off your debt,
會給你機會賣煙的
you'll get another chance at sales.
去他媽的
Fuck that.
你頂替她
Take her place.
如果你想干的話
If you wanted to.
好的  我會考慮看看的
Yeah, I'll think about it.
我不怕你
I ain't scared of you.
說吧  莫妮  說吧
Say it, Moni! Say it, Mo...
-學校里怎么樣  -還好
- Hey, so, how you doin' in school? - Okay.
-你喜歡其他孩子嗎  -他們還行
- You like them other kids? - They're okay.
有些人取笑我  說我是呆子
Some of them make fun of me. Say I'm a nerd.
還說我沒有手機
And I don't got a cell phone.
說我的名字照《老友記》里的控制狂取的
Say I must've got named after that tense girl on Friends.
凈是些胡說八道
Man, that's some bullshit.
你的名字是照著
You was named after
《愛情與籃球》里的莫妮卡取的
Monica from Love & Basketball,
是桑娜·萊瑟扮演的
played by Miss Sanaa Lathan,
她才不是假正經  她跟丹澤爾搞上了呢
who, by the way, is so un-uptight she hooked it up with Denzel.
他都已經結婚了
And he married!
媽媽說那是謠言
Ma says that's a rumor.
不是謠言  而且媽媽很無聊
It ain't no rumor. And Ma is boring anyway.
靠  那是我伙計馬丁嗎
Shit. Yo! Is that my boy Martin?
我以為他還在監獄里呢
I thought his ass in jail.
他上個月出獄的
He got out last month.
看看這個
Watch this.
沒門  我再打給你
No way. I'll hit you back.
你在這里干嘛  老兄
What you doing here, dawg?
我以為你在監獄里呢
I thought your ass was in jail.
拜托  我沒那么蠢
Oh, please. I'm too slick for that shit.
你好
Hi.
我在匹茲堡找了一份政府工作
I got a government job out at Pittsburgh.
你瘋了
This is crazy.
你一定要上樓來跟福滋打個招呼
Hey, you gotta come upstairs and say hey to Fozzie.
靠  福滋也在
Shit. Fozzie around, too?
他看到你的話肯定會尿褲子的
He's gonna wet himself when he sees you.
我要上樓十分鐘
Look, I'm gonna go upstairs for, like, 10 minutes.
你就待在這里  好嗎
You stay right here, all right?
等等
Hey, hey. Oh, hold up.
最多二十分鐘  我保證
Twenty minutes, tops. I promise.
愛你
Love you.
孩子  來抱個  不  好好抱個
Yo! Son, give me some. No, bring that shit in.
來吧  伙計
Come on, man!
你最后拿那些電燈泡怎么辦了
Hey, so what'd you end up doing with all them light bulbs?
你殺了我  啦啦啦
You slay me, dee, dee, dee.
旺達
Hey, Wanda.
我
I, um...
我想說對不起
I wanted to say I'm sorry.
有點太遲了
It's a little late for that.
是我搞砸了  事情進展得太快
I screwed up. Things were just moving so fast that...
我不小了  斯科特
I'm of an age, Scott.
你別占著茅坑不拉屎
You gotta shit or get off the pot.
再給我一次機會
Give me another chance.
我會搬進來的
I'll move in.
我會把榨汁機什么的都帶過來
I'll bring the Vitamix and everything.
我想念你
I miss you.
過來  親愛的
Come here, panda.
我也想念你
I missed you, too.
我研究了下女體解剖學
I've learned some things about the female anatomy
我想你會喜歡的
I think you might enjoy.
你對我朋友瑪麗薩做了什么
What the fuck did you do to my girl Maritza?
她們敲詐我
They were blackmailing me.
她什么都不會說的
She wasn't gonna say nothing.
你覺得她會讓我孩子他爸坐牢
You think she's trying to get my baby daddy locked up
讓他無法撫養孩子嗎
so he can't provide?
我不能冒這樣的險
That's not a risk I can take.
那是我監獄里的妹妹
That is my sister in here.
我一點都不喜歡那個賤人  可她是我家人
I don't even like the bitch. But she's family.
我應該怎么做  告訴我
What am I supposed to do? Tell me.
難道要讓這里的每個西班牙姑娘
Am I supposed to let every Spanish girl around here
都來欺負我
start pushing me around?
-上帝啊  -我是獄警
- Oh, good God. - I'm a CO.
你覺得要是他們看到
What do you think happens
我給犯人帶小瓶裝的酒會發生什么事
when they see me giving an inmate airplane bottles of Jaeger?
你不肯戴套的時候
Maybe you should've thought of it
怎么不想到這一點
when you didn't wanna wear a condom. Huh?
寶貝  我要出來了
"I'm gonna pull out, baby.
戴套子很難高潮
It takes so long to come with a rubber."
你明明知道  這不公平
That's not fair, and you know it.
滾蛋  我罵臟話了
Fuck you. I just used obscenity.
你要給我記過嗎
You gonna write me a shot?
-達婭  我  -襲警  記我一筆呀
- Daya, I'm... - Assaulting an officer. Write me a shot.
怎么  沒種的家伙  來呀
What, pussy? Come on. Huh?
我不會給你記過的
I'm not writing you a shot.
可是只要你想你就能記一筆  對嗎
But you could if you wanted to, right?
因為你可以選擇  你有這個權力
Because you have a choice. You have the power.
而我是個犯人
I'm an inmate.
我一無所有
I have nothing.
上帝啊  我討厭老年人
Jesus, I hate the elderly.
女士們先生們  有請下一位州參議員
Ladies and gentlemen, your next state senator.
你想要討論基礎設施
You wanna talk infrastructure
或者洪水水位之類的  真遺憾
or flood levels or whatever, too bad.
每次都是相同的問題
It's the same goddamn question every time.
不  安迪·魯尼
No, Andy Rooney,
我不會談你那操蛋的醫保制度
I am not gonna touch your fucking Medicare.
你說該說的  老頭兒會投票的
Say what you got to say. The geezers vote.
你覺得我的頭發看起來太閃了嗎
Do you think my hair looks too shiny?
《都市郵報》報道說
Hey, so, City Post is reporting
羅利的PAC得到了  叫什么來著
Rowley's PAC just got a major donation from,
political action committee 政治行動委員會
高爾夫球場那家伙的大筆捐款
what's-his-face, the golf-course guy.
他們估計有150萬美元
They put it at a million and a half.
我靠
Oh, fuck.
我敢打賭羅利肯定手舞足蹈得像只淫猴
I bet Rowley danced like a little monkey-whore for it, too,
那個賤人
that dick stain.
完了  我們死定了
That's it, then. We're fucked.
你可以走了  加文
You can take off, Gavin.
好的
Cool.
今天的演講很棒  先生
Great speech today, sir.
非常有感染力
It was very powerful.
聽著  我們不會放棄的
Listen, we're not giving up.
我們會想出解決的辦法  我們還有選擇
We'll figure this out. We've got options.
我很有壓力  寶貝
I am stressed, babe.
有個記者在死死追問利奇菲爾德的事
I have this reporter buzzing around Litchfield
《奧巴馬的戰爭》作者
他就像該死的鮑勃·伍德沃德
like a Bob fucking Woodward.
他什么都不會發現的  我保證
He's not gonna find anything. I promise.
聽他意思就是  "當然  老兄
It's like, "Sure, buddy.
我們還是操心下給女囚建豪華浴室的事吧
Let's worry about funding luxury bathrooms for these ladies,
雙淋浴噴頭  各種各種
dual-action shower heads, the works.
別去解決什么判決法的問題
Don't bother fixing the sentencing laws,
讓每個人都得到公平審判
guaranteeing a fair trial for everyone
和稱職的律師
and a competent lawyer."
不  不  給她們浴球就行了"
"No, no. Let's give 'em loofahs."
我知道  我知道
Yeah, I know. I know.
人有時候真目光短淺
People can be so small.
我們會贏的  我保證
We're gonna win. I promise.
然后我們可以來解決真正重要的問題
And then we can get to work fixing what's really important.
我們是好人  我們會拉到資金的
We're the good guys. We'll find the money.
我們會在奧爾巴尼買棟房子
We'll get a house in Albany.
也許終于有個孩子
Maybe finally have a kid.
如果你想要孩子
If you wanna have a kid,
你就得跟我上床
you might actually have to have sex with me.
你知道  我
You know, I'm...
我總是精疲力盡  這件事讓我心力交瘁
I'm exhausted all the time. This is so draining.
我知道  我很抱歉  我只是
I know. I'm sorry. I just...
我只是想感受到你想要我
I just wanna feel like you want me.
我不僅想要你  寶貝
I more than want you, babe.
我需要你
I need you.
你好  哥們
G'day, mate!
我開玩笑的  誰會那樣說呢
I'm just kidding. Who even says that?
我得離家一會兒
I had to get out of the house for a bit.
波麗今天很讓人厭煩
Polly has been a pill today.
我整個下午都在看孩子
I watched the baby all afternoon.
我跟她說出去兜兜風  隨便她做什么
I told her to go spin or whatever it is that she does.
結果等她回來
And then when she gets back,
她的情緒比之前更古怪
she's in an even weirder mood than before.
女人啊  是不是
Bitches. Am I right?
你怎么了  哥們
So what's up with you, mate?
我不敢進去
I'm afraid to get in.
這水真冷
The water is so cold.
你總是能說服我
You always talk me into things.
好吧
All right.
見鬼去吧
The hell with it.
我來啦
Here I come!
從樹上下去
Get out the tree!
我一般不碰樹的
I don't mess with trees, generally.
你為什么要偷偷摸摸鬼鬼祟祟的
Why are you sneaking around all stealth and shit?
你他媽又不是粉紅豹
You ain't the damn Pink Panther.
你真有趣  總是開開玩笑  插科打諢
You're funny, aren't you? Always joking, always clownin'.
這里還不能笑  那我們還能干嘛
We can't laugh in here, what else we got?
說得不錯
That's a fair point.
問題是如果你只會開玩笑
Problem is when jokes are all you've got.
你就像故事里的蟋蟀
You're like the grasshopper in the story.
活在當下  今朝有酒今朝醉的人
Living for today, having a fine time.
沒有責任  沒有計劃  沒有抱負
No responsibilities, no plans, no ambition.
及時行樂  對吧
Carpe diem, right?
比你聰明的人早就說過了
Somebody even smarter than you said that.
當年這句話或許還有些道理
Yeah, well, that probably worked back then
那時的人四十歲前還可能出去
when folks were expected to check out before 40.
如果你不努力創造未來
Thing is, if you're not building a future,
那是因為你不相信未來的存在
that's because you don't believe there is a future.
是你自暴自棄
You've given up on yourself.
你就是個廢物
You're a loser.
你瘋了嗎
Are you out of your mind?
我一直等你到半夜  都不知道你在哪里
I'm up waiting till midnight for you, no idea where you are.
一切都很好  我們只是晚回來了
Everything's cool. We got held up, is all.
這孩子才九歲  她衣服上居然有大麻味
The girl is nine years old. Her clothes reek of pot smoke.
她沒抽  我又不是神經病
She ain't smoke none. I ain't no psycho.
讓你帶她出門是我的錯
This is my fault for letting you take her.
你就是嫉妒她喜歡我比喜歡你多  承認吧
You just jealous 'cause she like me more than you. Admit it.
別給你自己臉上貼金
Don't you flatter yourself.
不管是誰
She would like anyone
難得出現  還送她禮物
who showed up here every once in a blue moon
她都會喜歡的  哪怕禮物來路不明
and gave her presents they didn't even come by honest.
該死的她是我女兒  我想做什么就做什么
I can do whatever I want with my own damn daughter!
你把她留在我這里的時候
You lost all right to call her your daughter
就再也沒資格當她媽媽了
when you left her here with me!
你覺得我沒資格  要不這樣
You think I lost my right? How about this?
要不我們告訴她真相  看看她會選誰
Why don't we tell her the truth and see who she choose?
你不許那么做
Don't you dare do that to her.
她現在夠大了
She old enough now.
你什么都不許跟她說
You ain't tellin' her nothin'
你就會自己走掉把她扔下
and then walk out and leave her.
你要告訴她  好啊  你去告訴她呀
You wanna tell her? Fine. You go on and tell her.
不過你要告訴她就得帶她走
But then you got to take her.
也許我會這么做的
Well, maybe I will.
你能給這孩子提供什么樣的照顧
And what kind of care are you gonna provide for that child?
你會每天去學校接她
You gonna pick her up every day from school,
帶她去上鋼琴課嗎
take her to her piano class?
你能給她編辮子嗎
You gonna braid her hair,
她生病的時候你能通宵陪她嗎
sit up at nights when she's sick,
她吐的時候你能跪下來給她清理干凈嗎
clean up her vomit down on your hands and knees?
怎么  你覺得我辦不到
What, you don't think I can do that shit?
那你帶她走呀
You take her, then.
如果你覺得撫養她你能做得比我好
If you think you can do a better job of raising her than me,
請便
be my guest.
帶她走  走呀
Take her. Go!
我怎么會知道呢
How should I know,
她什么都不告訴我
she doesn't tell me anything.
她整天畫些奇怪的畫
Spends all her time drawing her weird pictures.
你有花
You have a plant.
對  放溫室里
Yeah. For the greenhouse.
這是我家灌木叢里開出的迷迭香
It's rosemary from my bush at home.
是一個全新的品種
Grows into a whole new plant.
不管怎樣
Anyway,
很抱歉我昨天不得不采取嚴厲手段
sorry I had to crack the whip yesterday.
沒關系  就是
No, it's... It was...
這工作看起來也許很簡單  但并非如此
This job may look easy, but it isn't.
我有抱負  有一天我會成為典獄長的
I got ambition, you know? I could be warden one day.
記過配額指標能不能成功  誰知道呢
This whole shot-quota thing, who knows if it works?
管理層的人都喜歡有計劃
The people upstairs, they like plans.
他們喜歡積極主動
They like initiative.
你得向他們展示你很有手段
You got to show 'em you're operating.
我明白
I understand.
有些人一點抱負也沒有
Some people, they got no ambition at all.
他們就想得過且過  吃吃喝喝
They just wanna skate by, drink beer,
干得越少越好
do as little as possible.
比如盧斯奇
Luschek, for instance.
盧斯奇人很好
Luschek's nice.
當然  如果你喜歡那樣的話
Sure. If you like that kind of thing.
我喜歡跟他聊天
I like talking to him.
跟懂你每天在做什么的人聊天
It's nice chatting with someone
是很開心的
who gets what you do all day, you know?
比如工作的事
Like, work stuff.
好吧
Okay.
我把這個拿出去
I'm gonna bring this outside.
明天見
See you tomorrow.
她還是你的女兒  阿蕾達
She's still your daughter, Aleida.
記住你懷孕時的樣子
Remember how you were when you were pregnant.
我懷孕的時候  我跟我媽談過
When I was pregnant, I talked to my mother.
你確定要用這種字體
Yo, are you sure about this font?
真的嗎
Yo, yo, really?
本尼特不會提交瑪麗薩的材料的
Look, Bennett ain't gonna file the paperwork for Maritza.
他只是想給她個教訓
He was just trying to teach her a lesson.
她明天就會放出來的
She'll be out tomorrow.
我根本沒提瑪麗薩的事
I didn't say anything about Maritza.
可是你表現得很緊張
But you're acting like an uptight bitch.
只是因為你畫漫畫
Well, just because you're doing a comic
不代表你就要用漫畫體
doesn't mean you have to use Comic Sans.
什么  小心眼
What... Hater.
我從沒想到
I never would've thought
速溶咖啡可以用來畫眼影
instant coffee could be used for eye shadow.
是啊  寶貝  它味道不好
Oh, yeah, hon. I mean, it tastes like ass,
所以不如用作化妝品
so it's actually better as a cosmetic.
誰會想到卡普托養了只烏龜
Who would have thought that Caputo had a turtle?
我還以為他喜歡養鳥呢
I mean, I had him pegged as a bird guy.
女主編  干得怎么樣了
Madam Editor, how you doing?
我們其實都是副主編
We're actually all assistant editors here.
就像電視節目里
Oh, you mean like a TV show
所有名字都會在最前面滾動播放嗎
with all those names rolling by up front?
他們不可能都那么重要
They can't all be that important.
我向你保證每個人都是不可或缺的
I assure you that everyone here is vital to the operation.
好吧
Oh, okay.
看看這個  海利先生
Check this out, Mr. Healy.
這是什么
What's this?
漫畫
Comics.
很好的作品
Hey, good artwork.
海利先生
Hey, Mr. Healy,
不知道你有沒有聽說我準假申請的事
I was wondering if you've heard anything about my furlough.
你知道官僚作風  我會打電話問問的
Hey, bureaucracy, you know? I'll call around and check.
這是什么時候的事
Hey, when did this happen?
就是讓他不要纏著我們
That's just to keep him off our backs, you know.
自負
Ego.
聰明  查普曼
Good thinking, Chapman.
好吧  繼續干吧
All right, carry on.
那只海象真滑稽
That walrus is hilarious.
把我畫的給我
Give me my shit.
拿那個的地方還有很多
There's more where that came from.
我知道
I know.
因為酸奶就是我做起來的
Because I invented the yogurt thing.
有點創意行嗎  曼多薩
Have some originality, Mendoza, huh?
好吧  我沒想到會是這樣的
Okay, I didn't ask for any of this.
有等候名單  不過我會想辦法的
There's a waiting list, but I'll see what I can do.
你想要什么  泥漿面膜
What do you want? A nice mud mask?
還是口香糖
Or is it gum?
由于某種原因突然間每個人都想要口香糖
Everyone suddenly seems to want gum for some reason.
她們是要用包裝材料來做打火機
They're making lighters with the wrappers.
我一點都不喜歡這樣
I don't like this one bit.
拜托  她賣她的  你賣你的
Please. She sells her thing, you sell yours.
井水不犯河水
It's no competition.
所以你站在她那邊
So you're on her side?
不不  我不要黑市上的東西
No, no, no, no. I don't want no black-market shit.
我要香菜  你可以在花園種
I want cilantro. You can grow that in the garden.
成交
Deal.
-再種點辣椒  -別得寸進尺
- Some padron peppers? - Don't push it.
不過好吧
But fine.
那好
Fine then.
我要遲到了
I'm late for somethin'.
《獄中號角》
你總是把眼前的棋子都吃掉
You keep taking out all the targets in front of you,
可是你得想三步  蘇珊娜
but you've got to think ahead, Suzanne.
如果你走那里
If you move there,
我會怎么走呢
what'll I do?
這就叫放長線釣大魚
It's called the long game.
好吧
Okay.
好什么
Okay, what?
那差事我干
I'll take my medicine.
給她袋子
Give her the bag.
這是什么
What's this?
用過的衛生棉條
Used tampons.
不是衛生棉條
Not the tampons.
只是套管  垃圾桶里撿的
Just the tube-y parts. From the trash can.
你這是在整我吧
Now you just fuckin' with me.
衛生棉條在小賣部賣五美元
Tampons cost $5 at the commissary.
垃圾桶里用過的套管  免費
Used applicators out of the trash, they're free.
你以為第一批貨是怎么來的
Where do you think the first batch came from?
總有人得做
Somebody had to do it.
真惡心
This is disgusting.
的確如此
Yes, it is.
這可好
Great.
我口渴
I'm thirsty.
喝我給你的水
Drink the water I gave you.
我不要水  我要果汁
I don't want water. I want juice.
你得等我們過了安檢再說
Well, you're gonna have to wait till we get through security.
可我現在就口渴
But I'm thirsty now.
你有孩子嗎
Do you have kids?
沒有
Nope.
謝謝  我們走  寶貝
Thanks. Let's go, baby.
我不要去  我不要去  我不要去
I'm not going. I'm not going. I'm not going.
羅伯塔  別讓他們帶走我  羅伯塔
Roberta! Don't let them take me! Roberta!
羅伯塔  不要去  不要去
Roberta. Not going. Not going.
告訴我他們帶走她是為了幫她
Please tell me that they're taking her to get help.
他們帶她去公交站
They're taking her to the bus station.
她覺得林登·約翰遜是現任總統
She thinks that Lyndon Johnson is President.
第36任美國總統
她需要在專業機構接受全職護理
She needs full-time care in a dedicated facility.
放開我
Let go of me!
他們不會給她付錢的
They're not gonna pay for that.
她的家人呢
What about her family?
她有個女兒在斯德哥爾摩
She has a daughter in Stockholm.
可她們沒聯系
They don't speak.
那她就無家可歸了
So she's out on the street?
這叫"以人道理由獲釋"
It's called "compassionate release".
羅伯塔
Roberta!